ottawamommyclub.ca 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy 2 - Ottawa Mommy Club : Ottawa Mommy Club

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://ottawamommyclub.ca.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

Google Analytics: This [article](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) summarizes Google Analytics’ data practices and commitment to protecting the confidentiality and security of data. “At Google, we are keenly aware of the trust you place in us and our responsibility to keep your privacy and data secure. As part of this responsibility, we let you know what information we collect when you use our products and services, why we collect it, and how we use it to improve your experience. The [Google privacy policy & principles](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) describes how we treat personal information when you use Google’s products and services, including Google Analytics.”

**PromoSimple**

This [privacy policy](https://promosimple.com/privacy-policy) (the “Privacy Policy”) describes how Promo Simple, Inc. (“Promo Simple”, “We”, “Us”, or “Our”) collects and uses your data. We own and operate PromoSimple.com along with web services related to those sites (collectively, the “Service”).

### MailChimp

MailChimp reaffirms its commitment to safeguarding the personal data of our members, contacts, and anyone who visits our websites. MailChimp has three core privacy principles: accountability through awareness, empowering individuals, and protecting and safeguarding information.[Privacy Policy ](https://mailchimp.us17.list-manage.com/track/click?u=7408690b9f7fe1132e6e7422b&id=7a9a06212f&e=df99646a6f)and [Terms of Use](https://mailchimp.us17.list-manage.com/track/click?u=7408690b9f7fe1132e6e7422b&id=783ea9b5be&e=df99646a6f)

### **Jetpack by WordPress.com**

### Activity Log

**Data Used:** To deliver this functionality and record activities around site management, the following information is captured: user email address, user role, user login, user display name, WordPress.com and local user IDs, the activity to be recorded, the WordPress.com-connected site ID of the site on which the activity takes place, the site’s Jetpack version, and the timestamp of the activity. Some activities may also include the actor’s IP address (login attempts, for example) and user agent.

**Activity Tracked:** Login attempts/actions, post and page update and publish actions, comment/pingback submission and management actions, plugin and theme management actions, widget updates, user management actions, and the modification of other various site settings and options. Retention duration of activity data depends on the site’s plan and activity type. [See the complete list of currently-recorded activities (along with retention information)](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/activity-log/#data-retention).

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Successful and failed login attempts, which will include the actor’s IP address and user agent.

* * *

### Carousel

**Data Used:** If image view tracking is enabled, the following information is used: IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Image views.

* * *

**Data Used:** In order to process a comment like, the following information is used: WordPress.com user ID/username (you must be logged in to use this feature), the local site-specific user ID (if the user is signed in to the site on which the like occurred), and a true/false data point that tells us if the user liked a specific comment. If you perform a like action from [one of our mobile apps](https://apps.wordpress.com/mobile/), some additional information is used to track the activity: IP address, user agent, timestamp of event, blog ID, browser language, country code, and device info.

**Activity Tracked:** Comment likes.

* * *

### Contact Form

**Data Used:** If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, the contact form submission data — IP address, user agent, name, email address, website, and message — is submitted to the [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) service (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) for the sole purpose of spam checking. The actual submission data is stored in the database of the site on which it was submitted and is emailed directly to the owner of the form (i.e. the site author who published the page on which the contact form resides). This email will include the submitter’s IP address, timestamp, name, email address, website, and message.

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Post and post meta data associated with a user’s contact form submission. If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, the IP address and user agent originally submitted with the comment are synced, as well, as they are stored in post meta.

* * *

### Google Analytics

**Data Used:** Please refer to the appropriate [Google Analytics documentation](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsTrackingOverview#howAnalyticsGetsData) for the specific type of data it collects. For sites running [WooCommerce](https://woocommerce.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) and this feature simultaneously and having all purchase tracking explicitly enabled, purchase events will send Google Analytics the following information: order number, product id and name, product category, total cost, and quantity of items purchased. Google Analytics does offer [IP anonymization](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en), which can be enabled by the site owner.

**Activity Tracked:** This feature sends page view events (and potentially [video play events](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#video-hosting)) over to Google Analytics for consumption. For sites running WooCommerce-powered stores, some additional events are also sent to Google Analytics: shopping cart additions and removals, product listing views and clicks, product detail views, and purchases. Tracking for each specific WooCommerce event needs to be enabled by the site owner.

* * *

### Gravatar Hovercards

**Data Used:** This feature will send a hash of the user’s email address (if logged in to the site or WordPress.com — or if they submitted a comment on the site using their email address that is attached to an active Gravatar profile) to the [Gravatar](https://gravatar.com/) service (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) in order to retrieve their profile image.

* * *

### Infinite Scroll

**Data Used:** In order to record page views via [WordPress.com Stats](https://jetpack.com/support/wordpress-com-stats/) (which must be enabled for page view tracking here to work) with additional loads, the following information is used: IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Page views will be tracked with each additional load (i.e. when you scroll down to the bottom of the page and a new set of posts loads automatically). If the site owner has enabled [Google Analytics](https://jetpack.com/support/google-analytics/) to work with this feature, a page view event will also be sent to the appropriate Google Analytics account with each additional load.

* * *

**Data Used:** Commenter’s name, email address, and site URL (if provided via the comment form), timestamp, and IP address. Additionally, a jetpack.wordpress.com IFrame receives the following data: WordPress.com blog ID attached to the site, ID of the post on which the comment is being submitted, commenter’s local user ID (if available), commenter’s local username (if available), commenter’s site URL (if available), MD5 hash of the commenter’s email address (if available), and the comment content. If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) is enabled on the site, the following information is sent to the service for the sole purpose of spam checking: commenter’s name, email address, site URL, IP address, and user agent.

**Activity Tracked:** The comment author’s name, email address, and site URL (if provided during the comment submission) are stored in cookies. [Learn more about these cookies](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#comments).

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** All data and metadata (see above) associated with comments. This includes the status of the comment and, if [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, whether or not it was classified as spam by Akismet.

* * *

### Likes

**Data Used:** In order to process a post like action, the following information is used: IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID (on which the post was liked), post ID (of the post that was liked), user agent, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Post likes.

* * *

### Mobile Theme

**Data Used:** A visitor’s preference on viewing the mobile version of a site.

**Activity Tracked:** A cookie (`akm_mobile`) is stored for 3.5 days to remember whether or not a visitor of the site wishes to view its mobile version. [Learn more about this cookie](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#mobile-theme).

* * *

### Notifications

**Data Used:** IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. Some visitor-related information or activity may be sent to the site owner via this feature. This may include: email address, WordPress.com username, site URL, email address, comment content, follow actions, etc.

**Activity Tracked:** Sending notifications (i.e. when we send a notification to a particular user), opening notifications (i.e. when a user opens a notification that they receive), performing an action from within the notification panel (e.g. liking a comment or marking a comment as spam), and clicking on any link from within the notification panel/interface.

* * *

### Protect

**Data Used:** In order to check login activity and potentially block fraudulent attempts, the following information is used: attempting user’s IP address, attempting user’s email address/username (i.e. according to the value they were attempting to use during the login process), and all IP-related HTTP headers attached to the attempting user.

**Activity Tracked:** Failed login attempts (these include IP address and user agent). We also set a cookie (`jpp_math_pass`) for 1 day to remember if/when a user has successfully completed a math captcha to prove that they’re a real human. [Learn more about this cookie.](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#protect)

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Failed login attempts, which contain the user’s IP address, attempted username or email address, and user agent information.

* * *

### Search

**Data Used:** Any of the visitor-chosen search filters and query data in order to process a search request on the WordPress.com servers.

* * *

### Sharing

**Data Used:** When sharing content via email (this option is only available if [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is active on the site), the following information is used: sharing party’s name and email address (if the user is logged in, this information will be pulled directly from their account), IP address (for spam checking), user agent (for spam checking), and email body/content. This content will be sent to [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) so that a spam check can be performed. Additionally, if [reCAPTCHA](http://www.google.com/recaptcha) (by Google) is enabled by the site owner, the sharing party’s IP address will be shared with that service. You can find Google’s privacy policy [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

* * *

### Subscriptions

**Data Used:** To initiate and process subscriptions, the following information is used: subscriber’s email address and the ID of the post or comment (depending on the specific subscription being processed). In the event of a new subscription being initiated, we also collect some basic server data, including all of the subscribing user’s HTTP request headers, the IP address from which the subscribing user is viewing the page, and the URI which was given in order to access the page (`REQUEST_URI` and `DOCUMENT_URI`). This server data used for the exclusive purpose of monitoring and preventing abuse and spam.

**Activity Tracked:** [Functionality cookies](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#subscriptions) are set for a duration of **347 days** to remember a visitor’s blog and post subscription choices if, in fact, they have an active subscription.

* * *

**Data Used:** For video play tracking via [WordPress.com Stats](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#wordpress-com-stats), the following information is used: viewer’s IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. If [Google Analytics](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#google-analytics) is enabled, video play events will be sent there, as well.

**Activity Tracked:** Video plays.

* * *

### WordPress.com Secure Sign On

**Data Used:** User ID (local site and WordPress.com), role (e.g. administrator), email address, username and display name. Additionally, for activity tracking (see below): IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** The following usage events are recorded: starting the login process, completing the login process, failing the login process, successfully being redirected after login, and failing to be redirected after login. Several functionality cookies are also set, and these are detailed explicitly in our [Cookie documentation](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#sso).

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** The user ID and role of any user who successfully signed in via this feature.

* * *

### WordPress.com Stats

**Data Used:** IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. _Important:_ The site owner does **not** have access to any of this information via this feature. For example, a site owner can see that a specific post has 285 views, but he/she cannot see which specific users/accounts viewed that post. Stats logs — containing visitor IP addresses and WordPress.com usernames (if available) — are retained by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/) for 28 days and are used for the sole purpose of powering this feature.

**Activity Tracked:** Post and page views, [video plays](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#video-hosting) (if videos are hosted by WordPress.com), outbound link clicks, referring URLs and search engine terms, and country. When this module is enabled, Jetpack also tracks performance on each page load that includes the Javascript file used for tracking stats. This is exclusively for aggregate performance tracking across Jetpack sites in order to make sure that our plugin and code is not causing performance issues. This includes the tracking of page load times and resource loading duration (image files, Javascript files, CSS files, etc.). The site owner has the ability to force this feature [to honor DNT settings of visitors](https://jetpack.com/support/wordpress-com-stats/#honoring-dnt). By default, DNT is currently not honored.

* * *

### WordPress.com Toolbar

**Data Used:** Gravatar image URL of the logged-in user in order to display it in the toolbar and the WordPress.com user ID of the logged-in user. Additionally, for activity tracking (detailed below): IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Click actions within the toolbar.

### Plug in:

**Google Analytics Dashboard for WP (GADWP):** Displays Google Analytics Reports and Real-Time Statistics in your Dashboard. Automatically inserts the tracking code in every page of your website.Version 5.3.3 | By [ExactMetrics team](https://exactmetrics.com/) | [View details](https://ottawamommyclub.ca/wp-admin/plugin-install.php?tab=plugin-information&plugin=google-analytics-dashboard-for-wp&TB_iframe=true&width=600&height=550)

**Social Warfare:** A plugin to maximize social shares and drive more traffic using the fastest and most intelligent share buttons on the market, calls to action via in-post click-to-tweets, popular posts widgets based on share popularity, link-shortening, Google Analytics and much, much more! Version 3.0.7 | By [Warfare Plugins](http://warfareplugins.com/) | [View details](https://ottawamommyclub.ca/wp-admin/plugin-install.php?tab=plugin-information&plugin=social-warfare&TB_iframe=true&width=600&height=550)

**Really Simple SSL:** Really Simple SSL and Really Simple SSL add-ons do not process any personal identifiable information, so the GDPR does not apply to these plugins or usage of these plugins on your website. You can find our privacy policy [here](https://really-simple-ssl.com/privacy-statement/).

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Source: WP Recipe Maker

Bootstrapped Ventures, the developer of WP Recipe Maker, does not have access to any of the data collected by the plugin. This is all stored in your local database and not communicated back to us. Take note of the following topics for your own privacy policy.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When comment ratings are enabled we store the rating a user has given to a recipe along with the personal data WordPress core stores.

### Cookies

When user ratings are enabled we store a WPRM_User_Voted_%recipe% cookie (with %recipe% the ID of the recipe) that contains the rating this user has given to a particular recipe. This cookie is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

### IP Address

When user ratings are enabled we store the IP address upon voting. This is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

### Their own manually input information

With the Recipe Submission feature personal data can be collected, depending on the fields that were added to the form. This can include the user email and name. When using the reCAPTCHA feature you will be agreeing to their terms of use and privacy policy.

## How long we retain your data

Our cookies are stored for 30 days. User submitted data is stored indefinitely in the local database.

## Source: iThemes Security

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Security Logs

**Suggested text:  **The IP address of visitors, user ID of logged in users, and username of login attempts are conditionally logged to check for malicious activity and to protect the site from specific kinds of attacks. Examples of conditions when logging occurs include login attempts, log out requests, requests for suspicious URLs, changes to site content, and password updates. This information is retained for 14 days.

## Who we share your data with

This site is scanned for potential malware and vulnerabilities by Sucuri’s SiteCheck. We do not send personal information to Sucuri; however, Sucuri could find personal information posted publicly (such as in comments) during their scan. For more details, please see [Sucuri’s privacy policy](https://sucuri.net/privacy).

## How long we retain your data

Security logs are retained for 14 days.

## Where we send your data

This site is part of a network of sites that protect against distributed brute force attacks. To enable this protection, the IP address of visitors attempting to log into the site is shared with a service provided by ithemes.com. For privacy policy details, please see the [iThemes Privacy Policy](https://ithemes.com/privacy-policy)

## Source: Akismet

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

## Your Personal Information

### How we protect your data

We will not give out, sell, trade or rent your personal information or data.

### If you Unsubscribe from our Newsletter

If, at some time, you would like to unsubscribe to the Ottawa Mommy Club newsletter, your email address and any other information you have provided will be permanently removed.

## Information We Collect

When you subscribe the Ottawa Mommy Club newsletter, we require your email address to ensure you receive your weekly newsletters as well as contest alerts, and other special emails.  In addition, we ask for your name, email address, phone number, how you heard about us, how many children you have and their age.

We may also compile demographic information from members (such as children’s ages) to enable us to improve the content of our website and information we provide.  We may also use this compiled information (but  _never_  your individual personal information) to share with sponsors or advertisers.

We may contact you to inquire about your use of the Ottawa Mommy Club or to request additional information to help us make our site, and your experience better.  Your response to these inquiries is completely voluntary.

## Contests/Giveaways

  1. Contests are open to all Canadian Residents, unless otherwise stated.
  2. Entrants must be Age Of Majority in their province. Residents of Quebec are not eligible to win giveaways valued over $100 due to the contest policy of that province. Here are the current laws in this government of qc publication[http://www2.publicationsduquebec.gouv.qc.ca/dynamicSearch/telecharge.php?type=2&file=%2F%2FL_6%2FL6R6_A.htm](http://www2.publicationsduquebec.gouv.qc.ca/dynamicSearch/telecharge.php?type=2&file=%2F%2FL_6%2FL6R6_A.htm)
  3. Winners have 48 hours to claim their prize or a new winner is drawn, unless otherwise stated.
  4. One winner will be chosen at random using Random.org via PromoSimple.
  5. The winner’s first name might be posted at the top of the contest page and the news page on[ www.ottawamommyclub.ca](http://%20www.ottawamommyclub.ca/),  on our Facebook page [www.facebook.com/ottawamommy](http://www.facebook.com/ottawamommy) and/or Twitter page [www.twitter.com/OttawaMommyClub](http://www.twitter.com/OttawaMommyClub).
  6. The sponsor is responsible for shipping the winner their prize. Ottawa Mommy Club is not to be held responsible for events in which winners do not receive their prize.

## Additional Information

_Content:  _The Ottawa Mommy Club provides information about parenting, resources, family related issues, upcoming events and much more! Our goal is to bring out important information to Ottawa Moms. This information will be relevant to Ottawa and help enhance the lives of families residing in the Capital region.

The content of our website is intended for users who are over 18 yrs old.  Those under 18 may only use [www.ottawammmyclub.ca](https://ottawamommyclub.ca/privacy-policy/www.ottawamommyclub.ca) under the supervision of a parent or guardian and children’s personal information should never be entered on [www.ottawamommyclub.ca](https://ottawamommyclub.ca/privacy-policy/www.ottawamommyclub.ca).

_Policy Changes:_   www.ottawamommyclub.ca may make changes to its privacy and information policies.  When we do, those changes will be posted here.  Please check back to view our current privacy policies.

_Business Transfer:_  We might acquire other companies, which might include information about their customers.  If that happens, all reasonable efforts will be made to comply with the privacy policy of that company.  In the unlikely event that [www.ottawamommyclub.ca ](https://ottawamommyclub.ca/privacy-policy/www.ottawamommyclub.ca)or its assets are sold, customer information will be one of the assets which is transferred to the new owner.

## Editorial Policy

Ottawa Mommy Club content is determined by our Editor.  We select content which we believe will be the most relevant and interesting to our family focused readers.

Occasionally, we will feature content provided by our sponsors. When we do this, we’ll let you know in the advertisement headline on the article.  On occasion, we will send dedicated emails on our sponsors’ behalf.  These will be clearly marked, “Sponsor Email” or similar to identify them as paid content.

This policy is valid from May 23rd, 2018 to present.
